Guide to the Gary Hickling Collection on Lotte Lehmann ARS.0002
Stanford Archive of Recorded Sound
- Recordings
  - Lotte Lehmann, Lieder (not on LP)., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 8, Folder 63)
    Side 1: Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Feste Burg ist unser Gott (Chorale prelude), BWV 720 -- Russian trad. Ich bete an die Macht der Liebe -- Ratzinger, Georg. O du fröhliche -- Franz Xaver, 1787-1863. Weihnachtslied Stille Nacht! heil'ge Nacht! -- Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Wir glauben all an einen Gott (Chorale prelude), BWV 680 -- Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Lieder, op. 27. Morgen; Lieder, op. 56. Mit deinen blauen Augen -- Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Geheimes; Erlkönig -- Varlamov, Aleksandr Egorovich, 1801-1848. Rote Sarafan -- Apostel, Hans Erich, 1901-1972. Es waren zwei Königskinder (?) or Faisst, Clara, 1872-1948. Folksong. Es waren zwei Königskinder -- Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847. Gesänge, op. 19a. Gruss -- Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. O Heil'ger Geist, kehr bei uns ein; Bist du bei mir, geh' ich mit Freuden. Now attributed to Stölzel, Gottfried Heinrich, 1690-174 -- Berger. Ach wer das noch könnte. Side B: Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Gretchen am Spinnrade -- Traditional. Schlaf! holde Süsse -- Franz Xaver, 1787-1863. Weihnachtslied Stille Nacht! heil'ge Nacht! -- Silent Night! Holy Night -- Traditional. O come all ye faithful -- Bavarian folksong Zuschau'n -- Traditional. Schlaf' mein süsses -- Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Jesus, meine Zuversicht (Chorale prelude); Verschiedene Vorspiele über die Catechismus- und andere Gesänge. Aus tiefer Not schrei' ich zu dir, BWV 686 -- Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847. Gesänge, op. 47. Morgengruss -- Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Lieder, op. 49. Wiegenlied (in English) -- Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Kinderscenen. Träumerei -- Berlin, Irving, 1888- God bless America -- Molloy, James L., 1837-1909. Kerry dance
  - Pasatieri, Thomas. Lehmannlieder, 1988., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 8, Folder 64)
    Introductory speech by Judith Beckmann, former student of Lotte Lehmann. Performers: students from Music Academy of the West. Pasatieri, Thomas. Sieben Lehmannlieder -- various Schumann Lieder
  - Lehmann Lieder for Frances Holden., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 60 minutes (Othertype 8, Folder 65)
    Performer: Paul Ulanowsky, piano. Homemade copy of various Lotte Lehmann discs. The recording was a present for Frances Holden. Lieder by Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897 and Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949.
  - Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Walküre. Tape1 of 3., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo, 60 minutes (Othertype 8, Folder 66)
    Metropolitan Opera. Leinsdorf, Erich, 1912-, conductor. Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Walküre.
  - Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Walküre. Tape 2 of 3, 1 sound tape cassette; stereo, 60 minutes (Othertype 8, Folder 67)
    Metropolitan Opera. Leinsdorf, Erich, 1912 -, conductor Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Walküre. Act I - II part 2 - Act III part 1
  - Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Walküre. Tape 3 of 3., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo, 60 minutes (Othertype 8, Folder 68)
    Metropolitan Opera. Leinsdorf, Erich, 1912 -, conductor Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Walküre. Through Act III part 2 to end.
  - Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Walküre. Act II, 1936., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo, 90 minutes (Othertype 8, Folder 69)
    San Francisco Opera. Live performance Performers: Reiner, Fritz, 1888-1963, conductor; Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962 Melchior, Lauritz; Lotte Lehmann. Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Walküre. Act II.
  - Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Walküre. Act II, 1936., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 8, Folder 70)
    San Francisco Opera. Live performance Performers: Reiner, Fritz, 1888-1963, conductor; Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962 Melchior, Lauritz; Lotte Lehmann. Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Walküre. Act II. (Duplicate ?)
  - Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Lohengrin. Selections, 1931; Meistersinger von Nürnberg. Selections, 1935., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 60 minutes (Othertype 8, Folder 71)
    Vienna. Live performance. Side 1: Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Lohengrin. Excerpts. 1931. Side 2: Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Meistersinger von Nürnberg. Excerpts.
  - Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Lohengrin, 1935., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 60 minutes (Othertype 8, Folder 72)
    Live Metropolitan Opera Performance. Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Lohengrin. Excerpts.
  - Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Rosenkavalier (Opera). Act III, 1945., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 9, Folder 73)
    San Francisco Opera. Sébastian, Georges, 1903-, conductor. Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Rosenkavalier (Opera). Act III.
  - Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Rosenkavalier (Opera), 1933., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 9, Folder 74)
    Vienna Philharmonic Orchestra. Performers: Heger, Robert, conductor. Schumann, Elisabeth; Mayr, Richard, 1877-1935; Olszewska, Maria, 1892-1969; Lehmann, Lotte Commercial recording. Abridged version of Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Rosenkavalier (Opera).
  - Lehmann - Lieder and interview.1951; 1961, 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 9, Folder 75)
    Side 1: Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Selections -- An mein Clavier -- Schöne Müllerin. Neugierige -- Fischerweise -- Im Abendrot -- Seligkeit -- Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847. Gesänge, op. 86. Mond; Lieder, op. 57. Venetianisches Gondellied -- Cornelius, Peter, 1824-1874. Trauer und Trost. Ton. Side 2: Opera News on the Air. Metropolitan Opera. John Gutman (sp?) and Lotte Lehmann discuss Richard Strauss' Arabella and Der Rosenkavalier.
  - Talk on the Marshallin role in Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Der Rosenkavalier -- Various LIeder.1938; 1947; 1946, 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 9, Folder 76)
    Intermission speech by Lotte Lehmann on Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Rosenkavalier's Marshallin; Hollywood Bowl concert ,194?. Hollywood Bowl Symphony Orchestra Ormandy, Eugene, 1899-1985, conductor. Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Selections -- Lieder, op. 10. Allerseelen -- Lieder, op. 29. Traum durch die Dämmerung -- Lieder, op. 27. Morgen -- Lieder, op. 10. Zueignung -- Schwanengesang (Song cycle). Ständchen -- Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Lieder, op. 49. Wiegenlied (incomplete) -- Guest on Radio Show "Duffy's Tavern" with Ed Gardner, 1947 -- Seattle Symphony Ericker, cond. Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Selections -- Junge Nonne -- Jüngling an der Quelle -- Erlkönig; Side 2: Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Wesendonck-Lieder. Träume -- Lehár, Franz, 1870-1948. Eva. Wär' es auch nichts als ein Augenblick -- Meyer-Helmund, Erik, 1861-1932. Lieder, op. 21. Zauberlied -- Strauss, Johann, 1825-1899. Fledermaus. Csárdás
  - Lieder, opera excerpts and talk show: Duffy's Tavern Sketch., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 9, Folder 77)
    Side 1: Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Selections -- Frauenliebe und Leben (complete No.1-8, with orchestra accompaniment) -- Myrthen. Widmung -- Du bist wie eine Blume -- Strauss, Johann, 1825-1899. Fledermaus. Csárdás and Finale, Act II; Zigeunerbaron Finale Act I and Finale Act III; Side 2: Grechaninov, Aleksandr Tikhonovich, 1864-1956. My native Land (in English) -- Drink to me only with thine eyes -- Balough, Teresa. Visions (in English) -- Hahn, Reynaldo, 1875-1947. D'une prison -- Paladilhe, Emile, 1844-1926. Psyché -- Hahn, Reynaldo, 1875-1947 L'enamourée; Infidélité -- Duparc, Henri, 1848-1933. Vie antérieure -- Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Selections -- Lieder, op. 10. Zeitlose -- Lieder, op. 19. Wozu noch, Mädchen, soll es frommen --Schlichte Weisen. Du meines Herzens Krönelein -- Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Jüngling an der Quelle -- An die Nachtigall, D. 497 -- Refrainlieder. Männer sind méchant -- Duffy's Tavern, 1947. Sketch & "Archie's Little Love Song" (duplicate from tape 75)
  - Lehmann Centennial, 1988 -- Opera selections and Lieder., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 9, Folder 78)
    Side 1: Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Walküre. Du bist der Lenz; Hinweg! Hinweg! Flieh die Entweihte! -- Strauss, Johann, 1825-1899. Fledermaus. Csárdás; Rosenkavalier (Opera). Da geht er hin -- Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Fidelio (1814). Komm, Hoffnung -- Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Wesendonck-Lieder. Schmerzen -- Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Dichterliebe. Hör' ich das Liedchen klingen -- Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Selections -- Junge Nonne --Jüngling an der Quelle -- Erlkönig -- Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Wesendonck-Lieder. Träume. Side 2: Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Gesänge, op. 43. Mainacht -- Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Selections -- An die Musik -- Schwanengesang (Song cycle). Ständchen -- Erlkönig -- Winterreise. Gute Nacht -- Frühlingstraum -- Leiermann -- Schwanengesang (Song cycle). Doppelgänger -- Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Selections -- Dichterliebe. Ich grolle nicht -- Myrthen. Nussbaum -- Lotosblume.
  - Lotte Lehmann - Lieder and interviews., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 9, Folder 79)
    Performer: Ulanowsky, Paul, 1908-1968, piano. Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Romanzen und Lieder, op. 84. Vergebliches Ständchen; Lieder, op. 49. Wiegenlied -- Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Veilchen; Warnung -- Wolf, Hugo, 1860-1903. Mörike-Lieder. Gesang Weylas; Verborgenheit -- Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Selections -- Lieder, op. 10. Allerseelen -- Zueignung -- Lieder, op. 17. Ständchen -- Nacht und Träume. Side 2: Fassett, James interviews Lehmann and Schumann, Elisabeth on Feb. 5, 1950 -- Studs Terkel interviews Lehmann on April 18, 1960 -- Personal reflections of Lehmann by Bruno Walter for the London Wagner Society, May 1959 -- Personal reflections of Lotte Lehmann by Melchior, Lauritz for the London Wagner Society, May 1959.
  - Various songs., 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, mono.; 7 in. (Box 10, Folder 1)
    Songs with Orchestral accompaniment. Gruber, Franz Xaver, 1787-1863. Stille Nacht, Heilige Nacht (In English) -- Oakeley, Herbert Stanley, Sir, 1830-1903. O come, all ye faithful -- Bavarian folksong, Zuschau'n -- Traditional. Schlafe, mein süsses Kind --Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Jesus, meine Zuversicht (Chorale prelude); Verschiedene Vorspiele über die Catechismus- und andere Gesänge. Aus tiefer Not schrei' ich zu dir, BWV 686 -- Homeland Mine -- Worth, Amy Aldrich, 1888-1967. Midsummer -- Calcott. Drink to me only with thine eyes -- Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847. Gesänge, op. 47. Morgengruss.
  - Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Winterreise and miscellaneous songs., 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, mono.; 7 in. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    Performer: Ulanowsky, Paul, 1908-1968, piano. Side 1: Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Winterreise. No. 1 - 16 (tape damaged at end of side 1). Side 2: Lieder No. 16 - to 24. With orchestral accompaniment. Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Selections -- Myrthen. Widmung -- Du bist wie eine Blume -- Nussbaum -- Lieder und Gesänge, op. 77. Aufträge -- Wiegenlied -- Dichterliebe. Ich grolle nicht -- Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Tannhäuser. Allmächt'ge Jungfrau -- Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. An den Mond, D. 193; Schwanengesang (Song cycle). Ständchen
  - Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Frauenliebe und Leben and various Lieder., 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, mono.; 7 in. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Selections -- Frauenliebe und Leben -- Gedichte, op. 35. Alte Laute -- Myrthen. Du bist wie eine Blume -- Liederkreis, op. 39. Frühlingsnacht -- Franz, Robert, 1815-1892. Gesänge, op. 10. Für Musik; Gesänge, op. 5. Gute Nacht.
  - Various arias and Lieder., 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, mono.; 7 in. (Box 10, Folder 4)
    Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Tannhäuser. Allmächt'ge Jungfrau -- Homilius, Gottfried August, 1714-1785 (?) or Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. O Heil'ger Geist, kehr bei uns ein -- Stölzel, Gottfried Heinrich, 1690-1749. Bist du bei mir -- Children's song, Nun ein einziges mal -- Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Gretchen am Spinnrade; Wiegenlied, D. 498 -- Marx, Joseph, 1882-1964. Lieder und Gesänge. Selige Nacht -- Pfitzner, Hans Erich, 1869-1949. Lieder, op. 11. Gretel -- Thomas, Ambroise, 1811-1896. Mignon. Elle est aimée -- Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Nozze di Figaro. Deh vieni, non tardar.
  - Various Lieder., 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, mono.; 7 in. (Box 10, Folder 5)
    Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Gesänge, op. 43. Mainacht -- Wolf, Hugo, 1860-1903. Spanisches Liederbuch. In dem Schatten meiner Locken -- Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Gesänge, op. 31. Kartenlegerin; Liederkreis, op. 39. Waldesgespräch --Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Im Abendrot -- Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Lieder, op. 10. Allerseelen; Lieder, op. 10. Zueignung -- Varlamov, Aleksandr Egorovich, 1801-1848. Krasnyi sarafan -- Apostel, Hans Erich, 1901-1972. Es waren zwei Königskinder -- Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847. Gesänge, op. 19a. Gruss
  - Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Walküre. Act I, March 30, 1940., 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, mono.; 7 in. (Box 10, Folder 6)
    Metropolitan Opera Orchestra. Boston performance. Leinsdorf, Erich, 1912-, conductor. Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Walküre. Act I.
  - Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Walküre. Selections., 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, mono.; 7 in. (Box 10, Folder 7)
    Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Walküre. Selections.
  - Texaco Metropolitan Opera Broadcast: Metropolitan Marathon. Historical performances, 1987., 1 sound tape reel: analog, 1 7/8 ips, half-track, mono.; 7 in. (Box 10, Folder 8)
    Hawaii Public Radio, Robert Sherman and George Jelinek (sp?) hosts. Opera selections, and interviews with various opera singers. Performer: Milnes, Sherrill as Germont Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Traviata. Di Provenza il mar, 1970 -- Interview with Sherril Milnes on the "Verdi baritone." Performer: Bergonzi, Carlo Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Trovatore. Ah, sì, ben mio, 1960 Performer: Milanov, Zinka Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Trovatore. D'amor sull' ali rosee, 1938 -- Interview with Milanov, Zinka. Performers: Karajan, Herbert von, conductor; Adam, Theo as Wotan; Reynolds, Ana as Fricka. Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Walküre. Finale, 1969. Performers: Bodansky, Arthur, conductor; Lehmann, Lotte; Melchior, Lauritz. Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Lohengrin. Bridal chamber duet, archival recording, Dec. 1935 -- John Gusman (sp?) interviews Lehmann and Jeritza, Maria on their performance of Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Ariadne auf Naxos. Performers: Bohm, Carl, 1844-1920, conductor; Thomas, Jeff Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Ariadne auf Naxos. Metropolitan opera premiere, 1962. Final scene -- Interview with Troyanos, Tatiana on her trouser role as the composer in Struass' Ariadne. Performers: Levine, James, conductor; Troyanos, Tatiana as the composer. Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Ariadne auf Naxos. Seien wir wieder gut, 1976. Performers: Bodansky, Arthur, conductor; Melchior, Lauritz as Siegfried; Kettner, Anna as Nina Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Siegfried Act I, Jan. 1937 Performers: Stiedry, Fritz, conductor; Berger, Erna; Helm, Paul (?) Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Siegfried. Final Scene of Act II, 1951 Performers: Levine, James conductor; McIntyre, Donald as Wotan Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Walküre. Feuerzauber. Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten as Brünnhilde; Lauritz, Melchior as Siegfried. Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Siegfried, love duet, 1937 -- Robert Sherman interviews James Morris base-baritone. Performers: Rudel, Anthony J., conductor; Morris, James. Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880. Contes d'Hoffmann. Scintille, diamant. Performer: Milanov, Zinka Giordano, Umberto, 1867-1948. Andrea Chénier. Mamma morta, Dec. 1954 -- Robert Sherman interviews Norman, Jessie. Performers: Davis, Andrew conductor; Norman, Jessie as Ariadne. Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Ariadne auf Naxos. Es gibt ein Reich, 1985
  - Gausmann interviews Lotte Lehmann. Part I., 1 sound tape reel: analog, 15 ips, half-track, stereo.; 10 in. (Box 10, Folder 9)
    Bayrischer Rundfunk. Lehmann reminiscing on her career in Hamburg, Berlin and Vienna (in German) -- Broadcasting of earlier Lehmann recordings: Weber, Carl Maria von, 1786-1826. Freischütz. Leise, leise, fromme Weise -- Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Ariadne auf Naxos. Es gibt ein Reich -- Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Fidelio (1814). Komm, Hoffnung.
  - Gausmann interviews Lotte Lehmann. Part II., 1 sound tape reel: analog, 15 ips, half-track, stereo.; 10 in. (Box 10, Folder 10)
    Bayrischer Rundfunk. Lehmann talks about her work with Strauss, the different phases of her career as an opera singer, a Lieder performer, as a teacher, an author and even as a painter (in German) -- Broadcasting of earlier Lehmann recordings: Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Lohengrin. Einsam in trüben Tagen -- Pfitzner, Hans Erich, 1869-1949. Lieder, op. 11 No.5 Gretel -- Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Erlkönig -- Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Rosenkavalier (Opera). Da geht er hin -- Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Du holde Kunst.
  - Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Lohengrin., 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4ips, half-track, mono.; 7 in. (Box 10, Folder 11)
    Playback problem: Two synchronous tracks
    Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Lohengrin.
  - Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Walküre., 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4ips, half-track, mono.; 7 in. (Box 10, Folder 12)
    Playback problem: recording level too low
    Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Walküre
  - Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Walküre, 1940., 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4ips, half-track, mono.; 7 in. (Box 11, Folder 13)
    No access. Unplayable (mold)
  - Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Rosenkavalier (Opera), 1940., 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4ips, half-track, mono.; 7 in. (Box 11, Folder 14)
    Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Rosenkavalier.
  - Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Schöne Müllerin., 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4ips, half-track, mono.; 7 in. (Box 11, Folder 15)
    Recorded, 1942 Performers: Ulanowsky, Paul, 1908-1968, piano Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Schöne Müllerin. Selections. Recorded in 1936 Performers: Balogh, Ernö, 1897-, piano Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Schöne Müllerin. Selections -- Poulenc, Francis, 1899-1963. Gloria. Laudamus te -- Concerto in G minor for organ
  - Lotte Lehmann - Lieder., 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, mono.; 7 in. (Box 11, Folder 16)
    Performers: Balogh, Ernö, 1897-, piano. Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Selections -- Lieder, op. 107. Mädchen spricht -- Deutsche Volkslieder, WoO 33. Mein Mädel hat einen Rosenmund -- Lieder, op. 47. Botschaft -- Wolf, Hugo, 1860-1903. Selections -- Spanisches Liederbuch. In dem Schatten meiner Locken -- Goethe-Lieder. Anakreons Grab -- Performers: Ulanowsky, Paul, 1908-1968, piano. Wolf, Hugo, 1860-1903. Selections -- Mörike-Lieder. Auf ein altes Bild -- Italienisches Liederbuch. Auch kleine Dinge -- Mörike-Lieder. Peregrina I -- Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Ich liebe dich -- Pfitzner, Hans Erich, 1869-1949. Lieder, op. 11. Gretel -- Marx, Joseph, 1882-1964. Lieder und Gesänge. Selige Nacht -- Jensen, Adolf, 1837-1879. Gesänge, op. 1. Lehn' deine Wang' an meine Wang' -- Performers: Balogh, Erno, piano. Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Selections -- Refrainlieder. Männer sind méchant -- Erlkönig -- An die Musik -- Performers: Ulanowsky, Paul, 1908-1968, piano. Hindemith, Paul, 1895-1963. Marienleben, soprano, piano (1923) -- Rast auf der Flucht in Aegypten -- Die Weise von Liebe und Tod -- Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827.Egmont. Trommel gerühret -- Freudvoll und Leidvoll.
  - Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Fidelio., 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, mono.; 7 in. (Box 11, Folder 17)
    Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Fidelio.
  - New Friends of Music Recital, Feb. 10, 1946., 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, mono.; 7 in. (Box 11, Folder 18)
    Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Wanderer (Song), D. 489; Im Frühling (fragment). From Rhodes Collection 12 G 1043-51
  - Lotte Lehmann - Lieder., 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, mono.; 7 in. (Box 11, Folder 19)
    Performers: Lotte Lehmann Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Schwanengesang (Song cycle). Ständchen -- Duparc, Henri, 1848-1933. Vie antérieure -- Hahn, Reynaldo, 1875-1947. Infidélité -- Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Selections -- Schlichte Weisen. Du meines Herzens Krönelein -- Lieder, op. 10. Zeitlose -- Lieder, op. 19. Wozu noch, Mädchen, soll es frommen -- Hahn, Reynaldo, 1875-1947. Enamourée -- Paladilhe, Emile, 1844-1926. Psyché -- Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962 Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Ah, perfido -- Weber, Carl Maria von, 1786-1826. Oberon. Ocean, thou mighty monster -- Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Fidelio. Abscheulicher! Wo eilst du hin? -- Performers: Philharmonic Orchestra. Ormandy, Eugene, 1899-1985, conductor. Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Walküre. Du bist der Lenz; Ho-jo-to-ho! -- Lohengrin. Einsam in trüben Tagen -- Euch Lüften, die mein Klagen --Tannhäuser. Dich, teure Halle -- Allmächt'ge Jungfrau.
  - Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Winterreise., 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, mono.; 7 in. (Box 11, Folder 20)
    Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Winterreise
  - Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Winterreise, Lieder 1-9., 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, mono.; 7 in. (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Winterreise. Lieder, 10 -20., 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, mono.; 7 in. (Box 11, Folder 22)
    Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Winterreise. Selections.
  - Lotte Lehmann - Lieder, 1941., 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, mono.; 7 in. (Box 11, Folder 23)
    Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Selections -- Lieder und Gesänge, op. 32. Wie bist du, meine Königin -- Lieder, op. 96. Wir wandelten -- Lieder, op. 46. An die Nachtigall -- Lieder, op. 105. Auf dem Kirchhofe -- Deutsche Volkslieder, WoO 35. Erlaube mir -- Deutsche Volkslieder, WoO 35. Da unten im Tale -- Lieder, op. 48. Gang zum Liebchen -- Lieder, op. 47. Sonntag -- Lieder, op. 47. O liebliche Wangen -- Gesänge, op. 43. Mainacht -- Meyer-Helmund, Erik, 1861-1932. Lieder, op. 21. Zauberlied.
  - Lotte Lehmann - popular songs, Lieder and arias., 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, mono.; 7 in. (Box 11, Folder 24)
    Hildach, Eugen, 1849-1924. Lieder, op. 19. Lenz -- Lieder, violin, piano acc., op. 15. Spielmann -- Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Walküre. Du bist der Lenz -- Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Auf dem Wasser zu singen -- Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Gesänge, op. 43. Von ewiger Liebe.
  - Lotte Lehmann sings christmas songs and various Lieder., 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, mono.; 7 in. (Box 11, Folder 25)
    Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Feste Burg ist unser Gott (Chorale), BWV 302 -- Ich bete an -- Ratzinger, Georg. O du fröhliche, o du selige -- Gruber, Franz Xaver, 1787-1863. Stille Nacht, heilige Nacht -- Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Wir glauben all an einen Gott (Chorale) -- Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Lieder, op. 27. Morgen; Lieder, op. 56. Mit deinen blauen Augen -- Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Geheimes; Erlkönig.